<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– 2022</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release-Notes: February</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-status-panel">Data Plane Status Panel&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The previous release added a pop-up table that displayed statistics about a node’s connections to other node such as gateways. We’ve now moved most of this information to a new panel dedicated for this purpose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hovering over the Data Plane status indicator next to the node name still includes basic details about the number of gateways known and connected. And it includes a link to the new panel for more detail:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="data-plane-hover.png" alt="Data Plane Hover">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Clicking that link or just selecting the Data Plane panel from the left navigation bar will bring you to a new page showing much of the same detail as the &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2021/december/">previous pop-up table&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="data-plane-historical-stats">Data Plane Historical Stats&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You can now load historical latency data about a connection between this node and a connected gateway. Simply select the gateway from the table by clicking it, choose a start and end time and click &lt;code>Load&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="data-plane-view.png" alt="Data Plane View">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="portal-tool-improvements">Portal Tool Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="tool-setting-history">Tool Setting History&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A common pain point when using the tools within the Trustgrid Portal was that if you had to rerun a tool you had to reenter the values into the prompt. With this release Trustgrid is introducing an execution history that will make rerunning a tool much simpler for users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an example, if I run the Interface &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/tcp-port-test/">TCP Port Test&lt;/a> tool for the first time, the target IP and port will be the defaults 192.168.1.1 and port 80&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tcp-port-test.png" alt="TCP Port Test">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I change these to a new IP and port and run (e.g. 172.16.22.199 and port 22) and run the tool. The next time I run the tool these settings will be populated automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tcp-port-test-2.png" alt="TCP Port Test">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, I can click the History tab on the right to see the last few execution settings. I simply need to click apply to rerun one of the configurations listed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="history.png" alt="History">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="mtr-tool">MTR Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>MTR (or my trace route) is an alternative to the traditional traceroute tool that expands on the data gathered and reported in a number of ways. It can be run interactively to run continuously until stopped, gather additional statistics, report multiple paths more clearly and more. While this tool has been available from within the Terminal for some time, Trustgrid has now made this accessible directly from the portal user interface.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To use this new feature, the node must be running the latest Trustgrid package version (&lt;code>1.5.20220215-1159&lt;/code>) or newer&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>To run the tool, navigate to the Network → Interfaces section of a node and select the desired interface. Then click the MTR button.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="mtr-button.png" alt="MTR Button">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The default settings are to target the local loopback interface IP (&lt;code>127.0.0.1&lt;/code>) and run 10 times (&lt;code>-c 10&lt;/code>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="mtr-modal.png" alt="MTR Modal">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Change the target to the desired IP or host name and update the options. Some useful options include:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>-T&lt;/code> to use TCP instead of ICMP and can be combined with &lt;code>-P XXXX&lt;/code> to target a specific known listening port. This can be useful when targeting a Trustgrid gateway from and edge node. (e.g. &lt;code>-T -P 8443&lt;/code>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;code>-w&lt;/code> runs MTR in wide screen reporting mode. You will not see output on the screen until the &lt;code>-c&lt;/code> count has completed but the output will persist, unlike when run interactively where it is cleared from the screen at completion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>See the &lt;a href="https://manpages.ubuntu.com/manpages/bionic/man8/mtr.8.html">mtr man page&lt;/a> for additional options.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="interface-flows-tool">Interface Flows Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Under the Network → Interface section you will see a new “Flows” tool listed&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="flows-button.png" alt="Flows Button">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To use this new feature, the node must be running the latest Trustgrid package version (&lt;code>1.5.20220215-1159&lt;/code>) or newer&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This tool provides information about flows traversing an interface, similar to who the VPN “View Virtual Translations Table” tool shows flows traversing the VPN.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Launching the tool you have a number of options to filter the results. Or you can run without filters to return all flows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="flows-modal.png" alt="Flows Filter Options">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The resulting table lists the flow found on the interface. This can be sorted by column.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="terminate-flow.png" alt="Flows Table">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, any active flow can be Terminated (disconnected) from within the tool. You will be prompted to confirm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="terminate-flow-confirm.png" alt="Terminate Confirmation">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="network-interface-improvements">Network Interface Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="interface-speed-and-duplex">Interface Speed and Duplex&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Trustgrid portal now displays the negotiated speed and duplex values:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="eth0.png" alt="Interface Speed">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it now allows you to change from the default Auto negotiation setting to a manual setting. This is frequently necessary when the connected port is hard set to a speed and duplex value, which breaks auto negotiation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="speed.png" alt="Interface Speed">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="alert-improvements">Alert Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="alert-suppression-window-events">Alert Suppression Window Events&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An Alert Suppression Window prevents the Trustgrid system from sending notification to alarm channels for a scheduled period of time. This is useful for preventing noisy alerts during planned maintenance. Historically, correlating events to this time period required remembering when the maintenance occurred.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the suppression window is closed, either by cancelling or allowing it to expire, two events are created. One for the scheduled start:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="alarm-suppression.png" alt="Alarm Suppression Begin">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And another for the actual end time:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="alarm-suppression-end.png" alt="Alarm Suppression End">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These events are viewable at both the node and organization level to make it easy to correlate events to the maintenance window.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="override-domain-level-threshold-alerts">Override Domain Level Threshold Alerts&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Threshold alerts, such as CPU % or latency, can be configured to apply to all nodes within a domain. But sometimes it is necessary for a specific node to have different thresholds defined. With this release, the domain thresholds can be overridden.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you navigate to the Alerts panel of a node, you will see a section at the bottom titled Global Alerts. It will list all threshold alerts defined at the higher, domain level. Click the Override button to set a node specific value.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="threshold-override.png" alt="Override">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Define a new threshold value or duration&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="threshold.png" alt="Threshold Configuration">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After you click &lt;code>Save&lt;/code>, the value will have a yellow square to indicate it is an override.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="overridden-threshold.png" alt="Threshold Override">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="threshold-alerts-included-data-points">Threshold Alerts Included Data Points&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously it wasn’t always clear why a threshold alert, such as an alarm regarding latency, exceeded the configured threshold. Even if you connected immediate to the device and checked the latency might have returned to normal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the JSON payload sent to alarm &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/alarms/channels/">channels&lt;/a> (email, Slack, PagerDuty, etc.) can include the data points used to calculate the average that exceeded the threshold. This is in a new section called &lt;code>details&lt;/code> and the values are in pairs of the timestamp &lt;code>t&lt;/code> (unix time) and value &lt;code>v&lt;/code> (in milliseconds in the example below).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="td-card card">
&lt;div class="card-header bg-white">Alert Payload&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="card-body code p-l0 m-0">
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-JSON" data-lang="JSON">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">...&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#4e9a06">&amp;#34;details&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;values&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">[&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664460&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1310&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664520&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1310&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664580&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">31&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664640&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">31&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">},&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">{&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;t&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">1645664700&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">,&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#204a87;font-weight:bold">&amp;#34;v&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">:&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold">890&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> &lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">],&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold">}&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>&lt;span style="color:#a40000">...&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: March</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/march/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-panel-improvements">Data Plane Panel Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the February 2022 release we introduced the &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/">Data Plane status panel&lt;/a> for investigating connections between edge and gateway nodes. With this release we’ve added some tools to this panel. The new Ping and Test Performance tools are linked in the far right column of each gateway’s row.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="ping-test-performance.png" width="400px" />
&lt;h3 id="gateway-ping">Gateway Ping&lt;/h3>
&lt;img src="gateway-ping-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;p>The gateway ping tool will launch a ping inside the data plane tunnel between the node and the gateway, similar to ICMP ping. This can provide a more realtime view of latency between node and gateway compared to the RTT column (only loaded on refresh) and the historical data which provides a minute by minute view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="ping-output.png" alt="Ping Output">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="gateway-performance-tool">Gateway Performance Tool&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The gateway performance tool attempts to estimate the available upload bandwidth between a node and gateway.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="gateway-performance-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;p>By default this tool will attempt to send 10MB of data to the destination device. This then used to calculate the available bandwidth. Sending more data provides a more accurate estimate but be aware that other devices using the same internet circuit may experience degraded performance while the test is running.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="performance-output.png" alt="Gateway Performance Output">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The periods are posted for about every 1MB of data sent. If you see exclamation marks this can indicate lost packets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="tool-improvements">Tool Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="mtr-improvements">MTR Improvements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>MTR, which was &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/february/">recently added to the portal&lt;/a>, can be powerful troubleshooting tool, but it has many options which can be tricky for newer users. To simplify the use we’ve added a new user interface that provides graphical options for selecting common parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="mtr-modal.png" width="400px" />
&lt;h2 id="aws-instances-metadata">AWS Instances Metadata&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>When the Trustgrid software is deployed in AWS we can gather additional metadata about the underlying instance. With this release we have added the availability zone, instances type and instance ID to the Info panel available on every node.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="node-visor.png" alt="AWS Metadata">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="timestamps-for-virtual-network-changes">Timestamps for Virtual Network Changes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before changes are committed to a virtual network setting, such as the virtual network route table, they are listed in the Changes panel for approval. This made it easier to see if other users had outstanding changes that might be in conflict. However, it wasn’t clear if the other user just made that change or if it had been left accidentally. With this release we’ve added a timestamp that shows when the user saved the change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="modified-route.png" alt="Change Example">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: May</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/may/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="trustgrid-permissions-restructuring">Trustgrid Permissions Restructuring&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Trustgrid’s portal and API have used Role based permissions to manage access within the Trustgrid system. As Trustgrid has expanded our feature set, adding features like containers, and our user base have grown the predefined role structure has become a poor fit. Many times these new features required Trustgrid Support to grant access to users. Additionally, what each role could and could not do was opaque to customers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this release will be migrating to a &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/user-management/policies/">policy-based&lt;/a> approach that will allow customers to independently tailor permissions to meet their own use cases. Customers will also be able to see exactly what rights policies allow and what policy is granting a user access &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/user-management/users/#view-effective-permissions">directly in the portal&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This migration will also allow future enhancements such as automatic policy assignment based on group membership, resource based policies limiting users to specific nodes/clusters, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="how-it-works">How it Works&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The new policy permission works as such:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Users can be attached to one or more policy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Policies are defined that either allow or explicitly deny permissions or actions
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Permission are grouped according to the related feature/objects set
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Read allows a user to view that group of related objects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Modify will allow users to add, change or delete those objects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Additional actions such as running tools on a node can be allowed/denied&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A denied permission will override any allowed permission in another policy&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="migration-of-role-permissions-to-policies">Migration of Role Permissions to Policies&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid previously had 4 predefined roles. With this release these will be migrated into 5 new builtin policies, and an additional policy will be created. As part of this migration Trustgrid is also making sure these policies only include the “least-privileges” required to perform the intent of each of the previously defined roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the release process users previously assigned a role will be automatically assigned the corresponding policy or policies listed below&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below is a list of our historic roles and the policies that replace them plus any known changes. If users previously assigned a role lose a tool or function they need, they can either be attached to a higher level builtin policy with the appropriate permissions or a custom policy can be created and attached.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="monitor-now-tg-builtin-monitorhahahugoshortcode-s2-hbhb-policy">Monitor (now &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-monitor">tg-builtin-monitor&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Monitor no longer has access to troubleshooting tools. These were removed because some of these seemed to exceed the privileges required for the user types expected to have this role.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="operator-now-tg-builtin-operatorhahahugoshortcode-s3-hbhb-policy">Operator (now &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-operator">tg-builtin-operator&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>No changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="node-administrator-now-tg-builtin-node-adminhahahugoshortcode-s4-hbhb-policy">Node-Administrator (now &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-node-admin">tg-builtin-node-admin&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>No changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="administrator-now-tg-builtin-adminhahahugoshortcode-s5-hbhb-and-tg-builtin-access-adminhahahugoshortcode-s6-hbhb-policy">Administrator (now &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-admin">tg-builtin-admin&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/user-management/policies/#tg-builtin-access-admin">tg-builtin-access-admin&lt;/a> policy)&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The administrator role previously included both the ability to make almost all technical changes and the ability to control access and permission to the portal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trustgrid determined that these functions are separate and many companies may want to further restrict the access administration to a subset of users. The functions have been split into two policies:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>builtin-tg-admin - Full access to make technical changes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>builtin-tg-access-admin - Ability to add or invite users, change and attach policies, and configure Identity Providers&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>However, Trustgrid cannot determine who within an organization should and should not have each of these functions so during this migration any user that was previously assigned the Administrator role will be attached to both policies.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is highly recommended customers review which users are attached to the builtin-tg-access-admin policy and remove from those that do not require it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="provisioning-order-improvements">Provisioning Order Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="contacts-and-stakeholders">Contacts and Stakeholders&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Orders historically only had fields for a general order contact and a technical contact. With this release additional stakeholders can be listed (such as a project manager associated with the project or other executive contacts).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="stakeholders.png" alt="Stakeholders List">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The goal is to eventually provide a method to send status updates to all contacts in a more automated fashion as order progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="add-provisioning-contacts-for-your-organization">Add Provisioning Contacts for your Organization&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you have stakeholders that will frequently be used on orders, you can add them as Contacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="contacts.png" alt="Add Contact">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These will then be available to select in the stakeholders section of an order and will auto-polulate the fields&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="add-stakeholder.png" alt="Add Stakeholder">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="activity-report">Activity Report&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="activity-report.png" alt="Activity Report">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new Activity Report will list all orders that transitioned to the selected Status during the selected Time Range and the results can be exported as a CSV. This can be useful for tracking progress of provisioning projects over time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="rack-mount-field-added">Rack Mount Field Added&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Some Trustgrid hardware has the option of including rack mounts. Previously this was documented in notes, but with this release a field has been added. If an appliance type does not have a rack mount option this will show as “unavailable”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="rack-mounts.png" alt="Rack Mount">&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Access to the Provisioning section of the portal is not a part of a builtin policy at this time. Access admins should create policies to grant users orders permissions and attach to the appropriate users.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Release-Notes: June</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/release-notes/cloud/archive/2022/june/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="faster-node-overview-graphs">Faster Node Overview Graphs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With this release we have reduced the time it takes for the initial Overview graphs to load when you first navigate to the node.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-time-range-selector">New Time Range Selector&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Previously the Trustgrid portal used a few different time range selectors on different pages, none of which were the most user friendly. Trustgrid is standardizing on a new selector shown below which some key new abilities:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Change from Local (browser) time zone to UTC&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch from an Absolute (e.g June 1 at 10am to Jun 1 at 11am) to a Relative time (last X hours)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="time-picker.png" alt="Time Range Selector">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new selector is in use at:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Flow Logs - Advanced Search&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Plane - Gateway monitoring statistics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="data-plane-panel-improvements">Data Plane Panel Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="data-plane-monitor-graph">Data Plane Monitor Graph&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously the statistics for latency (visible after clicking on the name of a connected gateway) were shown in three separate graphs: min, max, and mean. This sometimes made it hard to compare as they had different scales. Now these data points are visible on a single graph. They can also be deselected with the graph scale adjusting automatically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tunnel-latency.png" alt="Tunnel Latency Graph">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="sort-peers-by-connected-status">Sort Peers by Connected Status&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Previously the connected status column didn’t allow you to sort. If you had a lot of connected peers and wanted to focus on disconnected ones it was a challenge. Now you can sort by clicking on the column header.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="node-location-tab">Node Location Tab&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a new Location panel under History on the node detail page. This page allows you to:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Specify the Latitude and Longitude of used to display the location of the node on the network map. You can utilize a map such as Google Maps to determine these coordinates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Specify the City, State, Country and Zip where the node is deployed. Currently this is for informational purposes only and does not update the Lat/Long coordinates.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="location-form.png" alt="Location View">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="flow-log-improvements">Flow Log Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In addition to the new time range selector, we have also improved how advanced searches return results. Previously, if your search included a long time range or was run on a node with a lot of flows the system could return partial results. Now we’ve added a “Load More” button and additional results will be returned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="load-more-button.png" alt="Load More Button">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="access-policy-improvements">Access Policy Improvements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We’ve added several improvements to the Access Policy table for a virtual network.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can now select and bulk delete rules&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New special destination object options:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>private&lt;/code> - all IP v4 blocks defined as private by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Private_network#Private_IPv4_addresses">RFC 1918&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>public&lt;/code> - public will cover all other IP v4 addresses&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>