<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– Remote Tools</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/</link><description>Recent content in Remote Tools on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tutorials: Ping Remote Virtual Host</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/ping-remote-virtual-host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/ping-remote-virtual-host/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Both the source and destination nodes should have a virtual management IP configured
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>There should be a unique IP under Node &amp;gt; Configuration &amp;gt; VPN &amp;gt; Virtual Management IP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the virtual network route configuration in your domain, a route should exist with the following settings:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Destination: node name (even if part of a cluster)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Destination CIDR: virtual management IP with a /32 suffix&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Metric: 1&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use the &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/">View Virtual Route Table&lt;/a> tool to verify both the source and destination nodes have valid, available routes to each other&amp;rsquo;s virtual management IP&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Need to know the virtual IP address of the inside NAT if targeting a local IP on the destination network&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Need to know the virtual management IP address of the destination node if only verifying VPN network connectivity&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info" role="alert">
The &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/gateway-tools/ping-remote-node/">Ping Remote Node&lt;/a> tool allows you to verify data plane communication by node name
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="usage">Usage&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select &lt;code>VPN&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>Network&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;code>Tools&lt;/code> button and select the &lt;code>Ping Remote Virtual Host&lt;/code> option from the &lt;code>Select a service&lt;/code> dropdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="ping-remote-modal.png" alt="Ping Remote Host Dialog">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Modify the host parameter to the target virtual IP address and click &lt;code>Execute&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A window will pop up with the content like below.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="ping-output.png" alt="Ping Output">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="responses">Responses&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are several configuration elements that need to be configured and working for a VPN deployment to be successful. When something is not configured correctly, the trustgrid node responds to an ICMP ping with a variety of different &amp;ldquo;Destination Unreachable&amp;rdquo; error messages that can indicate what exactly appears to be wrong. Here are the error responses the node may give when attempting to ping a remote machine through the VPN when something is amiss.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="destination-net-unknown">Destination Net Unknown&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This error means that the node cannot find an interface network binding with an inside and outside nat that match the requests source and destination IP. You should re-examine the inside and outside nats for the node interface that is receiving the packet, and make sure that an inside nat is defined that matches the source machines local IP and an outside nat that matches the virtual destination IP (or that no outside nat is present, which defaults to 1x1).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="destination-net-unreachable">Destination Net Unreachable&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This error means that the node cannot find a route defined at the domain/network level for the destination IP in this request. You should examine the domain route definitions and make sure that one is included for the virtual destination IP address you are trying to ping. Use the &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/">View Virtual Route Table&lt;/a> tool using the target IP as a filter to confirm the route exists and is available.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="destination-host-unreachable">Destination Host Unreachable&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This error indicates that there is a route defined for the ping dest IP, but that the destination node associated with the route is not currently connected to this node. You should look at the routes in the source node&amp;rsquo;s detail page in the portal and make sure that there is one included for the destination node that should be receiving the request.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="packet-filtered">Packet Filtered&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This error results when the ping request could not be performed do to the lack of a domain network ACL allowing the request. While this itself only indicates that ICMP traffic is not allowed between these two hosts in this direction, it can be used as a valuable indicator of a bigger policy issue. Check your ACL list in the portal to ensure that icmp are allowed between these to hosts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="destination-host-unknown">Destination Host Unknown&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This error happens when the ping packet made it to the destination node, but no set of inside/outside nats could be found that include the source and destination IPs of this request. Check the destination node VPN settings to ensure an inside NAT is present for the virtual destination IP of the request, and either an outside NAT exists and includes the virtual source IP, or no outside NAT is present, which defaults to 1x1.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="no-ping-response-error">No Ping Response Error&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When a ping sits there and no response is received, usually the best way to troubleshoot further is to &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/sniff-interface-traffic/">sniff interface traffic&lt;/a> with a filter of &lt;code>icmp and host &amp;lt;target-ip&amp;gt;&lt;/code> on the source and dest nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When troubleshooting, keep in mind that the lack of an error likely means one of the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The local node VPN interface that should be receiving the packet hasn&amp;rsquo;t been configured correctly.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The local firewall, router or target machine isn&amp;rsquo;t correctly routing packets to the source node.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is an ARP issue on either the source or destination node where the node isn&amp;rsquo;t responding correctly (&lt;code>tcpdump -i &amp;lt;data_nic&amp;gt; arp&lt;/code>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is no responding machine on the remote side!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: Sniff Interface Traffic</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/sniff-interface-traffic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/sniff-interface-traffic/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>The sniff interface traffic tool performs a traffic capture on the selected node, which can help troubleshoot connectivity issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Sniff Interface Traffic tool allows you to monitor traffic in real-time but there are certain instances where you need to be able to capture traffic to a file for further analysis. For example, intermittent issues may require leaving a capture running for an unknown period of time. Or, perhaps you need to review the application data within the packet payload.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Traffic Capture is started with a standard tcpdump filter, just like the sniff interface tool, and max capture file size. Once the capture is stopped the captured data is written to .pcap files which can then be transferred for review.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-warning" role="alert">
The pcap files will include the data payload of any communication captured. If a non-encrypted protocol (such as HTTP or FTP) is used this could be visible in clear text.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Because of the risk of data being visible, there are several restrictions and controls in place:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The permission to run this tool (&lt;code>node-advanced::service:tg-capture&lt;/code>) must be granted on a per-user basis. Not even administrators have this feature by default.
&lt;img src="pcap-permissions.png" alt="img">&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trustgrid employees are specifically denied the ability to run this tool. Trustgrid employees are not permitted to view data transferred through our devices, so please do not send us the resulting pcap files.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="accessing--using-sniff-interface-traffic">Accessing &amp;amp; Using Sniff Interface Traffic&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to capture traffic.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select &lt;code>Interfaces&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>Network&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the Sniff Traffic button&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="network-tools.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Set the appropriate parameters.&lt;br>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>iface&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The interface name&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>filter&lt;/th>
&lt;td>The tool utilizes &lt;a href="https://www.tcpdump.org/manpages/pcap-filter.7.html">TCPDump filtering syntax&lt;/a>, which can help isolate interesting traffic. The below filter would show only ICMP and TCP traffic&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;img src="filters.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click &lt;code>Execute&lt;/code> to view the captured traffic&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="sniff-output.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="transfer-pcap-files">Transfer PCAP Files&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that you have created the pcap files you will need to transfer them somewhere for analysis. The Trustgrid node has standard file transfer clients installed including scp, sftp, and ftp.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="on-a-local-network">On a Local Network&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If the destination file server is on the local network of the node you will use the standard Terminal tool to run the file transfer commands.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Navigate to the node&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open a terminal from the toolbar at the top right&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>You will need to ensure that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The node has a valid route to the destination server&amp;rsquo;s network&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any firewall between the node and destination server allows the traffic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The destination server is configured to allow the node IP to connect&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Once you are in the terminal with the above configured an example scp command would look something like &lt;code>scp ~/captures/capture-2021-07-16_17-59-23.pcap0 username@172.16.100.10:/captures/capture-2021-07-16_17-59-23.pcap&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="across-the-virtual-network">Across the Virtual Network&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If the destination file server is across a Trustgrid virtual network you will need to use the VPN Admin terminal to run the file transfer commands. This uses the nodes configured Virtual Management IP to communicate to remote resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Navigate to the node&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the VPN panel. You may need to select the virtual network to use, if your device is connected to multiple.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select the &lt;code>Admin Terminal&lt;/code> button from the tools dropdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="admin-terminal.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>You will need to ensure that:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The node has a virtual management IP assigned. The tool will not launch without this.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A route for the virtual management IP exists in the virtual network route table.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On the destination node, that a 1:1 NAT exists for the destination file server assigning it to a virtual IP.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A route that includes the destination file server&amp;rsquo;s VIP exists in the network route table.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A virtual network access policy exists that allows the source node&amp;rsquo;s virtual management IP to connect to the destination file server&amp;rsquo;s VIP on the required port for your protocol.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The destination side node has a valid route to the destination server&amp;rsquo;s network.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Any firewall between the node and destination server allows the traffic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The destination is configured to allow the node IP to connect.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Once you are in the admin terminal with the above configured, an example SCP command would look like &lt;code>scp ~/captures/capture-2021-07-16_17-59-23.pcap0 username@10.200.100.10:/captures/capture-2021-07-16_17-59-23.pcap&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="useful-filters">Useful Filters&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The below filters can be combined using &amp;ldquo;and&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;or&amp;rdquo; without quotes&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>You can filter based on protocol such as &amp;ldquo;tcp&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;udp&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;icmp&amp;rdquo; without quotes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Best practice is to filter for what you want to see rather than filter out what you don&amp;rsquo;t want to see&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To see only traffic for a specific host use &amp;ldquo;host x.x.x.x&amp;rdquo; with the IP address in place of the x.x.x.x&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To see only traffic for a specific port use &amp;ldquo;port XXXX&amp;rdquo; replacing the XXXX with the desired port number&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If capturing traffic on a clustered node, you should filter out the cluster port traffic. Typically port 9000 or 1975. E.g., &lt;code>not port 9000&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If capturing on the ETH0 - WAN Interface, you should filter out traffic to both Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s network (35.171.100.16/28) and your data plane gateways&amp;rsquo; network or public IP. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to identify the actual network or IPs. E.g., &lt;code>not net 35.171.100.16/28 and not net X.X.X.X/X&lt;/code> or &lt;code>not net 35.171.100.16/28 and not host X.X.X.X&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: TCP Port Test</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/tcp-port-test/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/tcp-port-test/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>The TCP Port Test tool initiates a TCP session with a target IP address and port to confirm fully layer 4 connectivity. This would be similar to using netcat or telnet to test connectivity to a TCP port.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="usage">Usage&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select &lt;code>Interfaces&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>Network&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;code>Interface TCP Port Test&lt;/code> button&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="network-tools.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Update the host with the target IP address and the port with the target TCP port. Click &lt;code>Execute&lt;/code> to test connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="config.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A new window will open with the results. If a new window does not open, check your browser&amp;rsquo;s pop-up blocker settings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A successful test will look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="success.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A failed connection will look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="failed.png" alt="img">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tutorials: View Virtual Route Table</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/tutorials/remote-tools/view-virtual-route-table/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="usage">Usage&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Login to the Trustgrid portal and navigate to the Node from which you want to test connectivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Select &lt;code>VPN&lt;/code> under the &lt;code>Network&lt;/code> section.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Click the &lt;code>Tools&lt;/code> button and click the &lt;code>View Virtual Routes&lt;/code> button&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="network-tools.png" alt="Virtual Network Tools">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A table will appear with routing information for the node.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="virtual-route-table.png" alt="Virtual Route Table">&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="analyzing-the-route-table">Analyzing the Route Table&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="route-availability">Route Availability&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If a route is available, its &lt;code>Active&lt;/code> column will show a green up arrow (&lt;i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-up" style="color: green;">&lt;/i>). If a route is not available, its &lt;code>Active&lt;/code> column will show a red down arrow (&lt;i class="fa-solid fa-arrow-down" style="color: red;">&lt;/i>).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="route-preference">Route Preference&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Routes will be selected based on the following order:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>In overlapping routes, the most specific route wins. For example, 10.20.0.51/32 takes precedence over 10.20.0.0/24.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If multiple matching routes exist, the route with the lowest metric wins. For example, a metric of 1 takes precedence over a metric of 50.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>