<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>– overview</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/categories/overview/</link><description>Recent content in overview on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/categories/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting-Started: Basic Architecture</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/basic-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/basic-architecture/</guid><description>
&lt;h3 id="cloud-components">Cloud Components&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Portal - The cloud management UI.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gatekeeper - Provides configuration updates to edge nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Zuul - Maintains persistent connection with &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> for reporting, &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/alarms/events/">events&lt;/a>, and updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API - The management API that exposes 100% of UI elements to automation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Repo - The APT repository that stores all firmware, OS, and &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/nodes/">node&lt;/a> updates.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="edge-components">Edge Components&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Node - The software that provides core functionality in the edge including &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/networking/">networking&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/security/">security&lt;/a>, compute, and management features. Edge nodes build outbound connections to gateway nodes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="use-cases">Use Cases&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Software Defined Networking - Create a mesh &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/networking/">network&lt;/a> that connects cloud applications to edge data with load balancing, &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/clusters/">clustering&lt;/a>, and failover managed through a portal or API.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edge Compute - Deploy applications to the edge to access datasets not appropriate for replication to the cloud due to &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/security/">security&lt;/a> or compliance concerns, latency, or cost.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Device Management - Manage thousands of &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> with advanced tools to reduce the burden of operations at enterprise scale.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Edge API - Integrate thousands of edge datasets with a single API interface and ETL functions executing at the edge.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security - Leverage Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s advanced &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/security/">security&lt;/a> to protect against a wide range of threats.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Getting-Started: Networking</title><link>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/networking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/getting-started/networking/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Trustgrid delivers a software defined wide area network (SD-WAN) that enables connectivity between cloud environments, data centers, and edge or on-premise hosts. Our robust networking feature set provides layer 3 and layer 4 network overlays with cloud management tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="types-of-connectivity">Types of Connectivity&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid establishes mutual TLS tunnels between &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> using mutual authentication. These tunnels between edge nodes and gateway nodes constitute the data plane of a Trustgrid network. Over this tunnel two distinct types of connectivity are supported, Layer 3 and Layer 4. Layer 3 supports &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">routed&lt;/a> traffic and Network Address Translation (NAT) to replicate traditional WAN connections. Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s Layer 4 networking uses reverse proxies to map local IP-port number combinations to remote hosts. Each connectivity type has distinct advantages and may be used for either gateway nodes or edge nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="layer-3-overview">Layer 3 Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The Trustgrid VPN feature provides the capability to securely route IP packets between networks. In this configuration, Trustgrid &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/nodes/">nodes&lt;/a> can operate as a distributed mesh virtual private network (VPN) that can allow applications to access remote data and services at layer 3 (L3) of the network OSI model. This is done by defining a virtual L3 network (similar to an Amazon VPC) and then selecting how edge node networks are exposed and translated into the the virtual address space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Layer 3 configuration is required for all Trustgrid networking deployments on the Gateway (data center / cloud) side. This allows the use of L3 or Layer 4 configurations for edge node deployments. Layer 3 connectivity enables easy support of many hosts at each side of the connection. This allows the replication of existing &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">routes&lt;/a> and subnets to minimize reconfiguration of any remote or local networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Layer 3 edge configuration is ideal in situations where there is an incomplete understanding of all traffic (source and destination hosts/ports) as it supports more permissive ACLs. It is required when using stateful protocols (except FTP) and other protocols such as SIP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All gateway nodes must be deployed using L3 networking in a two interface (management/data NIC) configuration.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="layer-4-overview">Layer 4 Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Trustgrid Layer 4 (L4) is only supported in edge configurations. Layer 4 networking enables a reverse proxy connection between the Gateway Node IP address:port number that maps directly to an on-premise host:port. Specific network plug-ins support stateful features like FTP using L4 connectivity. With Trustgrid&amp;rsquo;s L4 networks there is no concern of overlapping local IP subnets on either end of the tunnel because Trustgrid proxies the traffic. The source of all TCP/UDP traffic is the edge node interface, not the originating host. This is transparent to the hosts on either side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Layer 4 connectivity offers slightly better performance than L3 in specific types of traffic and is ideal when there is a single or few remote/edge hosts that are being accessed with deterministic traffic. Layer 4 edge nodes are usually easier to deploy at an edge site as they can avoid the configuration of a &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/domain/virtual-networks/">virtual network&lt;/a> overlay (NATs, ACLs, &lt;a href="https://trustgrid.github.io/docs/docs/domain/virtual-networks/routes/">Routes&lt;/a>, etc). Remote sites that desire to view the actual source of traffic should use Layer 3 for edge configurations as the source IP for all traffic in a Layer 4 connection is the edge node&amp;rsquo;s data IP address.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>